Hey everybody and welcome to the Friday wrap on Streamline Solopreneur, a short episode
where I talk about three things, what's on my mind this week, recommended reading
and something fun.
This is the show that helps you automate your business so you can take time off,
worry free, and hopefully this curation will help you think more about how you are
spending your time. I'm your host, Joe Casabona, and here's what's on my mind for
July 3rd, 2026.
It's about getting distracted.
This is a group of people I trust and they made some compelling arguments. My business
has been slow lately, and I don't feel like my mailing list is growing the way it
should.
They unanimously said, I shouldn't, making the argument that my audience probably
I don't like being on the platform, and if
I don't like being on the platform, then I'm not going to try to do it. Well,
thing I had been thinking about. And last October, right before my 40th birthday,
I finally deleted Facebook, Instagram, Twitter,
TikTok, most of my social profiles leaving me only on LinkedIn.
So trying to get back on a platform and then do it well, even though I don't like
being there, would be an incredible waste of time and resources.
So
taking both of these arguments, both from groups of people
I trust,
I sat back and thought about what actually grows my mailing list.
is this social platform growing my mailing list?
It's not more on that in the automation of the week segment, which is now public
by the way. But first reviewing my analytics and then with the help of Claude,
I realized that most of my good subscribers are coming from my own content on YouTube
and my podcast as well as speaking events.
This could be talks that I'm giving in real life or at virtual events or webinars,
and it makes sense. I both love teaching and I am good at it.
Instead of getting distracted with another social platform that I know all hate,
this is where I need to double down
YouTube, my podcast and other people's audiences
speaking and providing real value is how I grow my list.
Good thing I am speaking at a bunch of events this year,
you can head over to casabona.org/now to see those.
The point is this,
and a lot of it will be coming from honest, genuine people
that you trust.
But ultimately the advice is one factor in a decision.
Consider the source of the advice
and do small experiments to see what works best.
After all, most people who recommend a TV show
are not really saying
you'll like this show.
They are saying, I like this show,
and it's only when a bunch of people or a few trusted friends recommend a show to
me that I actually check it out.
It would be a big shift. I'd have to sign up with a new account and figure out a
new username, set up the profile, and then post consistently there, which I'm not
see if social actually works for me.
The data
is a little bit mixed now that I'm reviewing
It tells me, no, not really from a UTM standpoint, but as Claude is pointing out
to me,
the source for referring URLs,
more of them are coming from LinkedIn. So this does need to be a concerted effort
on my part, but still the data is overwhelming. My own content and teaching
are the ways that I get more people on my list.
So that's what's on my mind this week. It's about not getting distracted, spending
your time the right way.
But there's also
it's just kind of a check
with the Friday wrap up.
They take me 90 minutes or less to do, and they are fun for me 'cause I do like curating.
this curation will help you think more about your systems. Is is what I've been saying
for the past couple of months.
But that's been missing the mark for a a bunch of reasons.
I haven't really been talking about systems. I've just been talking about random
and honestly,
that's not what my whole thing is all about. Yes, the system is the feature.
It's the plane ticket, right? My friend Seth says, don't sell the plane ticket, sell
the destination. The system is the plane ticket.
Or my friend Kat says, you know, sell the chocolate cake, not the broccoli. The the
system is the broccoli.
What is the destination?
What is the chocolate cake
that
you may have heard in the new intro
wisely.
has been helping with that. It's been more of just like a fun pet project for me.
So I'm reasserting that mission,
which again, you may have caught in the intro.
I'm also doing two other things.
The first is changing recommended media to something fun. You may have also caught
that in the intro.
There was just too much overlap between recommended reading and recommended media.
And
honestly, I was kind of getting sick of recommending YouTube videos or, or albums
But beyond that, something fun
should be a reminder that there is more to life than working.
You started your business for time freedom. Something fun
will remind you to take time for yourself.
I'm also adding automation of the week to the podcast.
My near two month experiment of using that as the carrot to get people on the stick,
that is my mailing list didn't work
and I think I have a much stronger lead magnet now. So shout out to the one person
who joined my mailing list
because of that,
Those are the two that's like the smaller on my mind.
This show
is going to focus more on
time freedom so that you can stop missing the important moments in life.
Okay,
Recommended reading this week is from TechRadar. I watched Disney's next Gen audio
animatronic transform from a pirate
I am gonna be honest here, there were a lot of good stories that came across my desk
this week.
I had a bunch to choose from, but ultimately I picked this story not only
Disney has always been on the forefront of audio animatronics. When Walt himself
to a living, breathing Abraham Lincoln in a hundred years, it was a marvel. His face
moved. He stood tall and spoke, and his mouth moved accurately when he spoke.
Disney has been iterating on that very first audio animatronic
for the last 70 or so years,
and within the last 10 days, they did it again and really
knocked it out of the park.
And I am sharing this story because
sucking industry that's eroding work quality and human connection.
Lots of people are concerned with data centers getting put in their hometown, mine
included.
But this, this is
really,
and it's serving an important purpose. And this is, I want to directly quote Leslie
Evans, executive research and development Imagineer at Walt Disney Imagineering Research
and Development.
What a very long title.
she said,
we don't build technology for technology's sake.
Everything is about telling a great story to our guests,
This is a truly great use of technology. And something more of us should lean into
is, is
we don't build technology for technology's sake.
Again, I I can't help but mention AI here and I wonder how much of us are using these
new
large language models, agents or whatever productivity tools just to say we're using
them.
This is something that you should think about because
that's more wasted time, not saved time. And yes, we do need to experiment,
but they should be purpose data-driven experiments. Maybe that's like the mission
of this week's Friday wrap up.
Okay, let's move on to something fun as we go into a long weekend, at least here
in the United States. Happy Independence Day to all who celebrate,
I wanna share with you my latest Lego build,
the Nintendo game. Boy, there's a picture in the newsletter, which you can get over
at streamlined FM slash rap. I will try to include one in the description as well.
this is not that, but it is super cool. It is complete with working buttons that
give you feedback when you push them.
screens. It's really neat and I enjoyed building it. My kids enjoyed watching me
or helping me build it. So if you're looking for a relatively cheap, this is around
50 or 60 bucks fun activity this weekend, especially
if you are in the oppressive heat of the Northeast US or parts of Europe.
This is a fun one. I had a lot of time, a lot of fun time building it.
So that is my something fun. I hope you enjoyed that new segment. I'm, I think I'm
going to enjoy doing that as the new segment.
is using Claude with Kit. For all of my druthers about ai, I do use Claude every
day.
this isn't really an automation per se because it's not running routinely or automatically.
There are a few things I am doing with Claude,
um,
and Kit to run them automatically on a schedule,
I wanted to get some computer assisted data crunching done. And thanks to Kits MCPI
was able to do a bunch of cleanup. I was able to mark low engagement, likely spam
or fake emails, which I deleted, cleaning up my list, improving my deliverability.
I was also able to, and this is shout out to Kyle Adams here,
So I was able to use Kit to guess the first names based on the email addresses,
which goes a long way towards personalization, right? Instead of saying like, Hey,
there, or hello there, I'm greeting somebody by their first name and if you're interested,
let me know, like leave a comment.
And I will share,
like the exact heuristic I guess in a future episode for how I did this. But like
working with the large language model and its understanding of, of language and patterns,
it was able to confidently guess the first name of about 260 of the 600 something
people who don't have first names on my mailing list.
The other thing I did was split first and last names for anybody who used both.
I was also able to find my high engagement subscribers based on the signals I have
so I can interact with them more people who have purchased for me or, or sent a hand
And finally, I was able to crunch all of my data over the last two years to figure
out
where my subscribers coming from.
This was a much better task for the Kit MCP because the kit dashboard doesn't make
And so using my findings and circling back to what's been on my mind this
So it did give me some concrete data
and it gave me some things to try.
But that's it for this episode of the Friday Wrapup. If you enjoyed this, you should
join my newsletter over at streamlined fm slash rap. As a thank you, you'll get my
solopreneur system starter kit, which is the best way for you to create more time
and space in your business without wasting a bunch of time figuring out how to get
started.
Again, that's over at streamlined fm slash rap.
Thanks so much for listening, and until next time, I hope you find some space in
your weekend.